Kazi Namirur Rahman, PGD SCM, M.Sc. engg. in CSE

Mailing Address:

C/O: Kazi Namirur Rahman ATI, Siddirgonj, Narayangonj Mobile: +880 1730-706585

E-mail: namiruradcsec@gmail.com



Goal oriented Supply Chain Professional (6.8 years of Supply Chain Management expertise in reputed MNCs) looking for a position of Asst./ Head of Procurement at any reputed organization in order to provide an efficient procurement service to the business at a reasonable cost and balance financial control with efficient transaction execution.

## **Career Objectives:**

Implementing the latest procurement and supply chain concepts for an efficient supply chain procurement system.

## **Career Summary:**

I'm a Procurement Professional both import &local with over 6.8 years of experience of the industry of Apparel Labeling and Garments Accessories. Presently working for Checkpoint System Bangladesh Ltd in procurement & sourcing and have worked for University of Information Technology & Sciences (UITS), ERA info tech PVT ltd. (covering a span of 10 years). I have got world class corporate induction and assigned in various challenging roles. I have been recognized by my employers for my outstanding achievements too.

# **Educational Qualification:**

M.Sc. Engg in Computer Science & Engineering from Chittagong University (CU). CGPA: 3.65 out of 4[Passing year-2012].

B.Sc. (Honors) Computer Science & Engineering from Chittagong University (CU). CGPA: 3.48 out of 4[Passing year 2009].

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) from Gach Baria N.G. High School Chittagong. [2001]-Science Group.

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) from Muslim Educational Society College. Chittagong. [1999]-Science Group.

	<b>Attending year</b>	Institution	Result
Name of the course			
PGDSCM (Post Graduate	2018	ISCEA, Ohio,	Certified.
Diploma in Supply Chain		USA.	Certificate No:
Management)			PGDSCM-BD18-
			1006

# **Employment History:**

## **Current Employer:**

<u>1.Procurement Executive-supply chain Management (May 01,2017 to Till Date) and Purchase officer (August 01,2013 to April 2017):</u>

Checkpoint Systems Bangladesh Ltd (Canadian MNC & an operating division of CCL Industries Inc. Canada with 25,00 employees globally)

\*Joined as a Procurement officer. Later, promoted to procurement executive

## **Responsibilities:**

- > Sourcing & contacting new suppliers, raw material & negotiate with suppliers, survey market, collecting quotations and prepare comparative statement.
- > Design and implement supply chain management system that supports business
- > strategies adapted to change market conditions, new business opportunities, and cost reduction strategies.
- Internal Discussion Meeting with SCM team about local spares issues and solve.
- To prepare report of Monthly Saving, Open PO, supplier evaluation report & Goods in transit (GIT).
- ➤ Continuously monitoring, evaluating and improving supplier performance.
- > Monitoring to ensure delivery on time
- > Regularly contacting suppliers to renegotiate prices.
- > Developing sourcing strategies.
- Assist management in formulating, reviewing or updating supply chain policies and practices in accordance with new or changing policies, standards, regulations or laws and ensure adherence to those across all departments.
- Liaison with Factory team to maintain optimum stock level.
- Coordinating all import related works and communicating freight forwarder to in-house goods on time.
- > Closely work with finance team to support various Supply Chain Finance activities.
- ➤ Coordinating S&OP meeting in each month.
- Responsible for logistics activities related to import & export.
- Follow up Import Plan, L/C procedure and C&F
- ➤ Having Comprehensive knowledge on:
  - How to prepare BMR and Projection for material planning.
  - Shipping documents related to import/export.
  - Bond License and various procedures related to this.

# 2.Lecturer, Computer science & Engineering (23rd December 2010 to July 2013)

University of information Technology & Sciences. (UITS) a concern of PHP Group.

## **Responsibilities:**

- ➤ To take class assigned courses by Management.
- > To prepare question as per syllabus.
- ➤ Making tabulation & Result sheet.
- > Member of examination board & Cultural program.

## **Professional training Received:**

- ➤ Day long training on FSC (Forest stewardship council) details in PO through GRN by Checkpoint system.
- ➤ Workplace Efficiency and Productivity Improvement Exclusive Session for Personal & Professional Greatness.
- Training on Fire Safety Management by BUREAU VERITAS at Checkpoint systems Bd Ltd.
- ➤ Day long training on RSL (Restricted Substance List) of VF at Lakeshore Hotel by VF Bangladesh.
- ➤ How to handle EXPORT Document special in EPZ, Global Ethics policy, Vat and Tax, 5S, Undue Influence Policy (In-house Training by Check point system Bd Ltd.).
- > Training on Global Ethics policy, Vat and Tax, 5 S, Undue Influence Policy by Checkpoint system.

## **ERP Knowledge & Vendor Certified:**

- > SAP (Checkpoint system)
- ➤ Oracle-SDS (BASE)
- ➤ Negotiation skill & development.

#### IT Skills:

- > Operating System Linux: DOS, Windows XP, 2010.
- ➤ Programming Language: HTML, PHP, C, C++, Java.
- ➤ Internetworking Technologies: Adequate Knowledge about IP network and able to work with LAN, WAN Architectures, Peer-to-Peer and Client/Server System, Subnetting, fiber and wireless media.

## **Language Proficiency:**

Fluent in listening, reading, writing and speaking skill in both Bengali and English.

#### **Membership:**

- 1. Associate member of Bangladesh Computer Society (BCS).
- 2. Selected Internship member of Bangladesh Computer Council (BCC) Batch -8.

#### **Personal Details:**

Name : Kazi Namirur Rahman Father's Name : Kazi Abul Hossen. Mother's Name : Tahera Begum.

Present Address : C/O:Saira Nasim Villa, Omar Ali Matbar

Road Badsha Chairman Ghata, Chandgaon, Chittagong.

Permanent Address : Vill: Satbaria, P.O: Hazipara, P.S: Chandanaish. Dist: Chittagong.

Date of Birth : 12<sup>th</sup> June 1984

Religion : Muslim Marital Status : Married.

#### **Reference:**

- 1. Md. Abu Hasnat. Head of Human Resources & Administration, Bangladesh Honda Private Ltd.Cell:01737088660.
- 2. Kazi Mohiuddin. Group Chief Executive Officer (CEO), Babylon Group. Cell: 01766670002.